Ronaldo Ortiz

Aspiring senior Full Stack Web Developer obsessed with learning and improving my current skills and building websites and apps at the same time.

La Paz ronyortizop@gmail.com 59177799006

I am a Web Developer who enjoys working with JavaScript and its ecosystem. My goal is becoming a senior Full Stack Web Developer in the next 2 years. Currently I am focused on learning and applying the ins and outs of vanilla JavaScript and React.js on the front-end, and Node.js, Express, and MongoDB on the back-end.

At this point I consider myself proficient and solid with the fundamentals of JavaScript and React.js and maybe a little more. On the other hand I have started already the back-end journey focusing on the MERN stack which has been an amazing and fun trip so far. I particularly enjoy working with databases since I used to work with Excel and Sequel Server doing CRUD for strategic business reports previous to my web development career, so I'm really passionate about this area.

Finally, when it comes to work alone or with a team, I feel confident that I can deliver quality results and can adjust to a fast paced environment with tight deadlines. I know how to plan and execute tasks within the required standards and I will always put my best in what I am assigned because, as I mentioned, I enjoy working in this field.

Please visit my portfolio website made entirely with React.js, following the link in the "Links" area below.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

Web Developer

Webdevbro (Owner) - La Paz September 2015 to Present

I started this entrepreneurship in 2015 with the main goal of providing affordable and cost-effective websites to small and medium businesses and organizations in Bolivia. At that time I used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL, to create custom websites using WordPress. I became a WordPress Theme Developer.

In 2020 I decided to drop WordPress as the supporting platform for creating websites and started diving deep into vanilla JavaScript and its ecosystem. Currently I build websites and applications using JavaScript and React.js, and for now, I use headless CMSs such as Strapi or Sanity, until I become proficient with Node.js. and the whole MERN stack, which I hope is going to be soon.

Digital Marketing Consultant

Pleiades Digital (Owner) - La Paz June 2012 to August 2015 I started my own company as a freelance Digital Marketing Consultant. At that time my area of expertise was business administration and marketing. The products/services I sold were:

- A comprehensive business plan for the main areas of the company.
- Creating a solid marketing strategy based on research of target markets, competition, product quality and other variables.
- Creating a full customer database that would resemble a CRM.
- Other business consulting as requested.

Education

Master's in Business Administration in Business

St. Edward's University - Austin, TX

September 2001 to June 2003

Skills

- React (1 year)
- JavaScript (4 years)
- HTML5 (6 years)
- CSS (6 years)
- Git (4 years)
- Node.js (1 year)
- GraphQL (Less than 1 year)
- MongoDB (1 year)
- Express.js (1 year)
- Material UI (1 year)
- TypeScript (Less than 1 year)
- Adobe Photoshop (2 years)
- Adobe Illustrator (2 years)
- Adobe XD (1 year)
- UX (1 year)
- Strapi (1 year)
- APIs (1 year)

Languages

• English - Fluent

Links

https://webdevbro.com

Additional Information

Workplace English (US) — Expert January 2020

https://share.indeedassessments.com/share_to_profile/b740e488037df73d501f09815e45b7bdeed53dc074545cb7